<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal blog on Javier Fernández</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/index.json</link><description>Recent content in Personal blog on Javier Fernández</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://javifm.com/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrate stylelint in Vue project</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/integrate-stylelint-in-vue-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/integrate-stylelint-in-vue-project/</guid><description>Stylelint is to CSS the equivalent to ESLint to Javascript. Until today, I was using CSS validation integrated in VSCode, but if we want to go further preventing errors or getting a better style consistency, a linter to CSS is the best option.</description></item><item><title>Oceanic Wind for VSCode</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/oceanic-wind-for-vscode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/oceanic-wind-for-vscode/</guid><description>I have created a VSCode dark theme called Oceanic Wind, but, why did I do that? Well, I have been using Oceanic Next theme for many years, first time I used it with Sublime Text, and I wanted to tweak it.</description></item><item><title>Setting up StandardJS</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/setting-up-standardjs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/setting-up-standardjs/</guid><description>In this post, we will cover the setup of StandardJS in VSCode to fix all the errors when saving a file automatically.
What is StandardJS? Initially, you could think that StandardJS is the standard used for Javascript code, and, that is its main goal: provide a style guide, linter and, formatter for Javascript.</description></item><item><title>Vue 3 with Typescript, ESLint and Prettier</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/vue-3-with-typescript-eslint-and-prettier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/vue-3-with-typescript-eslint-and-prettier/</guid><description>At the beginning of this year I started learning Vue 3, I had worked with version 2 before and the new version allows us to still use the same syntax, besides we can use the new Composition API, which is more powerful and customizable when creating reusable elements.</description></item><item><title>Responsive images in Hugo</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/responsive-images-in-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/responsive-images-in-hugo/</guid><description>In this post I will share a very useful shortcode that will allow us processing images automatically with Hugo. First of all, we must be sure that our content is structured in Hugo´s page bundles.</description></item><item><title>Search in Hugo with Lunr</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/search-in-hugo-with-lunr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/search-in-hugo-with-lunr/</guid><description>¿What is the best way to make a search engine in Hugo? My first attempt was looking for information in the official documentation, I found some guides and links which helped me, but none of them suited my needs.</description></item><item><title>Using TailwindCSS with Angular</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/using-tailwindcss-with-angular/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/using-tailwindcss-with-angular/</guid><description>In this article we are going to explain how to set up an Angular application with Angular CLI in order to integrate TailwindCSS. With this approach the CSS written in our components will be very little because most of the time we will be using Tailwind classes.</description></item><item><title>Using Tailwind CSS with Hugo</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/using-tailwind-css-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 13:08:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/using-tailwind-css-with-hugo/</guid><description>In this article we are going to see how can we build our Hugo site with TailwindCSS. Hugo is very flexible and allows us setting up our site easily as we want.</description></item><item><title>New website with Hugo</title><link>https://javifm.com/en/blog/new-website-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 12:04:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://javifm.com/en/blog/new-website-with-hugo/</guid><description>I have a new web with a single purpose: create articles with content about things I am learning. I have migrated the old posts from my Wordpress blog. I always wanted to create a design for my blog from scratch and finally I did it!</description></item></channel></rss>